Matt Caloger

Software Developer

With over a year of software development experience and five years of experience in the Information Technology field, I am a well-rounded developer skilled at building, deploying, and maintaining reliable software using modern and proven technologies.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer Consultant @ Self-Employed Nov 2021 → Current - Toronto, ON, Canada

- Providing software development and IT services to clients
- Developing a variety of full-stack open/closed source applications using a wide array of languages & technologies
- Building Java APIs using the Spring framework to manage web routing, logging, data access, and testing
- Producing JavaScript & TypeScript code to deliver React & Angular front-end user interfaces
- Creating C# applications using ASP.Net Core Web API/MVC along with Entity Framework Core for data access
- Packaging applications for deployment using Docker
- Setting up Linux VPS environments to serve applications using the Apache web server for serving and proxying requests and System-d for service configuration
- Managing data access using a variety of database servers and configurations, including SQLite, H2, Postgres, and SQL Server
- Designing user interfaces and iconography using Figma, Photoshop, and Illustrator

IT Support Specialist @ Tyndale University Jan 2020 → Nov 2021 - Toronto, ON, Canada

- Wrote software to improve and automate organization processes
- Built a Java/Spring scheduled printer resource reader that utilized Selenium to perform web scraping of printer admin interfaces
- Developed a custom Support Ticket system using PHP to improve user experience
- Spearheaded Active Directory automation using PowerShell scripts

Support Specialist I @ Atlantic Health Systems May 2016 → Dec 2017 - Morristown, NJ, USA

- Developed and maintained a WinForms-based C#/.Net application to significantly improve an internal process, which became the IT organizational standard
- Scripted WMIC queries to collect computer and installation information

Connect

- (416) 912-1451
- % Website Caloger.com
- % GitHub Github.com/mattcaloger

Featured Projects

Stasher

An application that allows users to securely share one-time messages with password-based encryption.

% https://stasher.caloger.com/

Budgie

A budget management application with a focus on data visualization. % https://budgie.caloger.com/

Skills

Programming Languages

Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, C#, PHP, SQL, PowerShell

Frameworks

Spring, JPA/Hibernate, React, Angular, Node, ASP.Net Core, Entity

Platforms

Docker, Apache Server, Heroku, Linux, Windows, MacOS

Developer Tools

Git, Visual Studio/Code, IntelliJ, Selenium

Concepts

Unit/Integration Testing, MVC, Single-Page Applications, Authentication/Authorization

Design

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

Information Systems

Project Management, Software Deployment, Documentation Writing

Education

Associate of Science in Information Systems @ Sussex County Community College Graduated 2021 - Newton, NJ, USA